Pinki Thakor

Front End Developer

Pinkithakor7874@gmail.com | +1 (613) 879-5314 | 52 Drinkwater Road, Brampton, ON L6Y4T9 / <u>LinkedIn</u>

Career Summary

I am a dedicated full-stack developer and designer with one year of experience in frontend web developments. My primary focus is on building Front-End Web Applications, hybrid, and Native Mobile Applications. My background in graphic design and web development allow me to fuse both the art and technology world together in perfect harmony making me a valuable asset for any team.

Education

Diploma, Mobile Application Design & Development

September 2018 - April 2020 | Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON

Computer Application and Information Technology

July 2014 - May 2017 | Shri Sarvajanik MSC(CA&IT) College, Mehsana, India

Skills

Markup Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript (ES6), C, C#, Xamarin, PHP

Frameworks, Libraries & Interface: Bootstrap, ReactJS, React Native, Restful APIs, Ajax, NPM, Cordova, Wordpress

Server Technologies: Node.js, Apache, MAMP and WAMP, Firebase, Heroku

Design Tools & IDE: illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Sketch, InVision, Visual studio, intellliJ, Android Studio, XCode, Bracket, Trello

Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Version Management: Git, GitHub, and Gitbucket

OS: Mac, Window, Linux

Experience

UX/UI Designer | The Launch Lab

Feb 2021 - Current | Ottawa, ON

- Design website layouts and architecture to maximize user experience and SEO
- Experience performing user research, user mapping, and presenting results.
- Illustrate design ideas using storyboards, process flows and sitemaps
- Design graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs and widgets
- Build page navigation buttons and search fields
- Develop UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems (e.g. responsiveness)
- Conduct layout adjustments based on user feedback

Front-End web developer & designer | Inovinta group of company

October 2020 - April 2021 | Sudbury, ON

- Utilize storyboarding and graphic pre-designs where appropriate.
- Responsible for the design and development of web pages, graphics, multimedia, and consultation on software UI's.
- Responsible for the development of web applications and components.
- Effectively develop clean, well structured, easily maintainable formats.
- Design skills: knowledge of typography, spatial orientation, the handling and manipulation of images, freehand graphics, and basic design elements.

Full-Stack Web Developer | Algonquin college of applied arts and technology

Jan 2020 - April 2020 | Ottawa ON

- Worked for experify health hospital to implement Full-stack web Application; participated in the complete life cycle of the project.
- Participated in the analysis, design, and development of different modules for integration with the application.
- Responsible for UI/UX design, testing, and client documentation.
- Played a key role in implementing responsive web app by using the latest technology.
- Work in backend database integration and deployment.
- Use technology like HTML5, CSS3, React, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6) Node.js, Git, Trello, illustrator, Adobe XD, MySQL, Heroku server.

Jr Web Developer | The One Web Technology

August 2017 - May 2018 | India, Gujarat

- Worked for the one web technology; responsible for the development, maintaining, and updating website.
- writing codes for creating responsive websites for multiple platforms.
- Worked in developing code to access a REST web service using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and convert the response into a JSON object.
- resolving complaints of customers and responding to their suggestions to improve the products.
- Assisting in the deployment and development of websites.

Noteworthy Projects

Volunteer Portal App | Experify Health Hospital

Jan 2020 - April 2020 | Ottawa ON

- With team Developed Volunteers App for Experify Health Hospital to do online volunteering for residents' home and hospitals.
- In this app we did user research and prepared UI and UX design.
- According UI developed hybrid for multi-platform
- For fronted we used React.js and for backed We have used Node.js and Heroku server for deployed the app.
- Utilized technologies like GitHub, Trello, and Slack for collaborating with team members allowing efficient code and project management

Pizza App Full Stack Web Application

April - 2019 | Ottawa, ON

- Lead a team for developing an online pizza ordering portal called "Pizza Pizza"
- Highly focused on front-end, back-end, and user authentication
- Improved users experience by 15% by easy to use User Interface
- Technologies Used: JavaScript (ES6), Node JS, Mongo DB, edumedia (college server), CSS3 and HTML5

Xamarin UWP App | Window Application

April - 2020 | Ottawa, ON

- Its single page Xamarin UWP window application. It Connected to the Microsoft Cognitive Service Vision API to use with a variety of image sources.
- Camera access used image source for the Vision API
- A Web image server used an image source for the Vision API
- Access to local images used as an image source for the Vision API
- A Cross-platform speech synthesizer used to speak the image description
- confidence level and image tags returned from the Microsoft Cognitive Services REST API

Reference